Register of the Lev E. Dobriansky papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Correspondence, 1960-1982 (Boxes 1-4)
  - Walsh, Patrick, 1981 (Box-folder 4: 17)
  - Walsh, William F., 1976 (Box-folder 4: 18)
  - Watson, Jack H., 1977 (Box-folder 4: 19)
  - Watson, Thomas J., 1960 (Box-folder 4: 20)
  - Weiman, Carlos F., 1965 (Box-folder 4: 21)
  - Weld, Stephen M., 1977 (Box-folder 4: 22)
  - Wetzel, John C., 1978 (Box-folder 4: 23)
  - Wexler, Anne, 1978 (Box-folder 4: 24)
  - White, Natalie, 1963 (Box-folder 4: 25)
  - White, Ray M., 1963 (Box-folder 4: 26)
  - Williams, Harrison A., 1976 (Box-folder 4: 27)
  - Willoughby, William F., 1977 (Box-folder 4: 28)
  - Wilson, Bob, 1963 (Box-folder 4: 29)
  - Wilson, Charles H., 1963 (Box-folder 4: 30)
  - Wolff, Lester L., 1976 (Box-folder 4: 31)
  - Woo, Jae-Seung, 1977 (Box-folder 4: 32)
  - Wurfel, Walter, 1977 (Box-folder 4: 33)
  - Wyatt, Wendell, 1965 (Box-folder 4: 34)
  - Wydler, John W., 1965 (Box-folder 4: 35)
  - Yatron, Gus, 1976 (Box-folder 4: 36)
  - Yi, Qu Hyong, 1979 (Box-folder 4: 37)
  - Young, Milton R., 1962 (Box-folder 4: 38)
  - Zablocki, Clement J., 1977-1981 (Box-folder 4: 39)
  - Zorinksy, Edward, 1982 (Box-folder 4: 40)
- Speeches and Writings, 1959-1982 (Box 4)
  Composed of printed speeches, writings, and an interview. The speeches were delivered at anti-communist advocacy conferences and to promote the Captive Nations Proclamation to House and Senate members. Dobriansky also advocated for captive nations through his writings. Subject matter includes the Captive Nations Proclamation and Captive Nations Week, designed to raise awareness about the abuses that took place in non-democratic countries. Also included is an interview of Dobriansky by The Washington Times regarding East-West relations, highlights from his organization’s accomplishments, and the Captive Nations List. Arranged by physical form, then chronologically thereunder.
  - Interview of Lev E. Dobriansky by The Washington Times, 1982 July 19 (Box-folder 4: 41)
  - Speeches, 1964-1977
    - "A Background of Failures and Defects, Fallacies and Omissions," Committee on Resolutions, Republican National Convention, San Francisco, 1964 July 9 (Box-folder 4: 42)
    - "Symbol of a Political-Cultural Lag," United States and Union of Soviet Socialist Republics Consular Convention, 1967 February 17 (Box-folder 4: 43)
    - "The Political-Economic Significance of US-USSR Trade,", 1975 October 3-4 (Box-folder 4: 44)
    - "Just Telling It Like It Is," Twelfth Quadrennial Congress of Ukranian Congress Committee of America, 1976 October 8 (Box-folder 4: 45)
    - "The USA Salutes Free China," anti-communist rally, World Anti-Communist League Conference, Taipei, 1977 April 22 (Box-folder 4: 46)
    - "Human Rights and U.S. Foreign Policy," Legislative Yuan, Taipei, 1977 April 23 (Box-folder 4: 47)
    - "Helsinki, Human Rights and U.S. Foreign Policy," Commision on Security and Cooperation in Europe, 1977 April 28 (Box-folder 4: 48)
    - "Whose Shoes Are You Wearing?," Manor Junior College commencement, 1977 May 12 (Box-folder 4: 49)
    - "The United States Senate Statement," Hearings on Genocide Convention, 1977 May 27 (Box-folder 4: 50)
  - Writings, 1959-1979
    - "The Captive Nations Week Resolution," The Ukrainian Quarterly, 1959 November (Box-folder 4: 51)
    - "Outstanding U.S. Myths on the Captive Nations," Ukrainian Quarterly, 1965 Summer (Box-folder 4: 52)
    - "Ten Reasons Against the US-USSR Consular Treaty," Ukrainian Quarterly, 1965 Winter (Box-folder 4: 53)
    - "Forget the Captive Nations?," Washington Report, 1966 July 18 (Box-folder 4: 54)
    - "Red Nightmare, Freedom's Hope," Ukrainian Quarterly, 1966 Summer (Box-folder 4: 55)
    - "Red Nightmare, Freedom's Hope," National Captive Nations Committee, 1966 July 19 (Box-folder 4: 56)
    - "Review of U.S. Policy Toward the USSR," Ukrainian Quarterly, 1967 Spring (Box-folder 4: 57)
    - The New Captive Nations, American Educational League pamphlet, 1975 June (Box-folder 4: 58)
    - "Another Captive Nations Week," National Review, 1979 December 21 (Box-folder 4: 59)
    - "The Captive Nations--Like God--Dead?,", undated (Box-folder 4: 60)
- American Council for World Freedom File, 1970-1980 (Box 4)
  The American Council for World Freedom was a non-government organization that promoted freedom and peace for non-democratic countries, especially those controlled by communist governments. Series includes press releases, newsletters, and a sourcebook.
  - Newsletters, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 4: 61)
    Include reports and updates from the American Council for World Freedom, news coverage of nations under communist domination, and the observance of Captive Nations Week.
  - Press releases, 1970-1980 (Box-folder 4: 62)
    Press releases cover the aftermath of the U.S. and USSR Detente Conference and the Belgrade Conference on Human Rights, including the Council’s official condemnation of President Ford’s statement denying any Soviet Union presence in Eastern Europe.
  - Source book, Human Rights after Helsinki, 1977 (Box-folder 4: 63)
    Includes articles related to problems within the Soviet Union and the effects of communism throughout mainland China, Cuba, and Eastern Europe.
- National Captive Nations Committee File, 1959-1982 (Boxes 4-7)
  Contains correspondence, press releases, proclamations, resolutions, pamphlets, newspaper clippings, audio tape reel, memoranda, general letters, flyers, programs, and booklets relating to the function of the Committee and its anti-communist advocacy for captive nations. Subject matter includes the sponsoring of the Captive Nations Award, the annual Captive Nations Week, and other advocacy efforts for non-democratic countries. Also included are incoming and outgoing correspondence from Daniel H. Flood and Donald L. Miller, both members of Congress and co-chairmen of the National Captive Nations Committee. Letters reflect their work on the Committee and in passing the annual resolution for Captive Nations Week.
  - Audio tape reel, Captive Nations luncheon, 1969 (Box-folder 4: 64)
  - Bicentennial salute, 1976 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - Commemorative programs, 1961-1982 (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - Correspondence, 1960-1980
    - Daniel J. Flood, 1962-1979
      - Alexandrakis, Manelas, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 3)
      - Antovich, Mike D., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 4)
      - Audenas, Juozas, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 5)
      - Backis, Stasys, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 6)
      - Balancy, Guy, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 7)
      - Balkenwas, John, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 8)
      - Ball, Luella, 1962, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 9)
      - Baum, William, 1978 (Box-folder 5: 10)
      - deBear, Larrye, 1976 (Box-folder 5: 11)
      - Bennet, Robert F., 1978 (Box-folder 5: 12)
      - Bercik, Steven J., 1963 (Box-folder 5: 13)
      - Bindzi, Benoit, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 14)
      - Boorstin, Daniel J., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 15)
      - Bowden, Otis R., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 16)
      - Brada, George, 1976 (Box-folder 5: 17)
      - Briscoe, Dolph, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 18)
      - van Burren, John E., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 19)
      - Camille, Patti A., 1976 (Box-folder 5: 20)
      - Carter, Jimmy, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 21)
      - Carvel, Elbert N., 1963 (Box-folder 5: 22)
      - Cash, Denise, 1978 (Box-folder 5: 23)
      - Castro, Raul H., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 24)
      - Cauas, Jorge, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 25)
      - Clift, Denis A., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 26)
      - Colby, W. E., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 27)
      - Comesanas, Raul, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 28)
      - Cross, John, 1967 (Box-folder 5: 29)
      - Curtis, Kenneth M., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 30)
      - Dinbergs, A., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 31)
      - Eizenstat, Stuart, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 32)
      - Fall, Louis, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 33)
      - Feulner, Edwin J., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 34)
      - Fisher, John M., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 35)
      - Ford, John, 1979 (Box-folder 5: 36)
      - Graves, Gerald W., 1978 (Box-folder 5: 37)
      - Han, Lih-wu, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 38)
      - Hatfield, Mark O., 1965 (Box-folder 5: 39)
      - Herzog, C., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 40)
      - Hesburgh, Theodore M., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 41)
      - Holland, Arthur J., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 42)
      - Holland, Clarence A., 1976 (Box-folder 5: 43)
      - Hong, Sung Chul, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 44)
      - Hsieh, Jen-chao, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 45)
      - Hunt, John P., 1963 (Box-folder 5: 46)
      - Johnson, Patricia, 1978 (Box-folder 5: 47)
      - Jones, Bill, 1963 (Box-folder 5: 48)
      - Kirks, Rowland, F., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 49)
      - Kraft, Tim, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 50)
      - Ku, Cheng-kang, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 51)
      - Lacour, Henry J., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 52)
      - Leonhart, William, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 53)
      - Liming, Robert G., 1978 (Box-folder 5: 54)
      - Link, Arthur A., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 55)
      - Mackie, George, 1965 (Box-folder 5: 56)
      - Margain, Hugo B., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 57)
      - Marsh, John O., 1976 (Box-folder 5: 58)
      - Mcintyre, Victor C., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 59)
      - McNichols, W. H., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 60)
      - Medvid, Nicholas, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 61)
      - Merridew, R. P., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 62)
      - Metcalf, Phyllis C., 1978 (Box-folder 5: 63)
      - Milliken, William G., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 64)
      - Olson, Richard E., 1978 (Box-folder 5: 65)
      - Pillard, Charles H., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 66)
      - Pritchard, Martha U., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 67)
      - Pryor, David, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 68)
      - Rankin, Edward S., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 69)
      - Ray, Robert D., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 70)
      - Read, Leonard E., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 71)
      - Reagan, Ronald, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 72)
      - Roberts, Linda D., 1978 (Box-folder 5: 73)
      - Ross, Jocelyn, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 74)
      - Ryan, Michael B., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 75)
      - Sacasa, Guillermo, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 76)
      - Salomon, Georges, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 77)
      - Sandner, Alois W., 1976-1979 (Box-folder 5: 78)
      - Schaefer, William D., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 79)
      - Shen, James H., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 80)
      - Smith, Odell M., 1963 (Box-folder 5: 81)
      - Soto, Horacio V., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 82)
      - Staar, Richard F., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 83)
      - Stenvig, Charles, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 84)
      - Stetsko, Yaroslaw, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 85)
      - Suwansiri, Sukho, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 86)
      - Szczydluk, Orest, 1965 (Box-folder 5: 87)
      - Wheeler, Charles B., 1977 (Box-folder 5: 88)
    - Donald L. Miller, 1960-1980
      - Barry, Robert R., 1963 (Box-folder 5: 89)
      - Bartkus, Eugene A., 1965 (Box-folder 5: 90)
      - Bosilievic, Joseph V., 1967 (Box-folder 5: 91)
      - Cahn, Julius N., 1966 (Box-folder 5: 92)
      - Chafee, John H., 1965 (Box-folder 5: 93)
      - Chamberlin, John, 1965 (Box-folder 5: 94)
      - Chopiwskyi, Walter, 1980 (Box-folder 5: 95)
      - Coleman, A., 1965 (Box-folder 5: 96)
      - Conte, Silvio O., 1961 (Box-folder 5: 97)
      - Courtney, W. T., 1966 (Box-folder 5: 98)
      - Day, Irving M., 1960 (Box-folder 5: 99)
      - Dunton, James G., 1960 (Box-folder 5: 100)
      - Fascell, Dante, 1965 (Box-folder 5: 101)
      - Folkard, David J., 1965 (Box-folder 5: 102)
      - Friend, James, 1965 (Box-folder 5: 103)
      - Harris, Frederick B., 1967 (Box-folder 5: 104)
      - Hart, Phillip A., 1961 (Box-folder 6: 1)
      - Heiling, Julie, 1965 (Box-folder 6: 2)
      - Henning, R. J., 1966 (Box-folder 6: 3)
      - Heyden, Francis J., 1967 (Box-folder 6: 4)
      - Javits, Jacob K., 1961 (Box-folder 6: 5)
      - Komichak, Michael, 1965 (Box-folder 6: 6)
      - Lester, Roy T., 1963 (Box-folder 6: 7)
      - Maher, Edward, 1963 (Box-folder 6: 8)
      - Marsh, John O., 1963 (Box-folder 6: 9)
      - Meany, George, 1965 (Box-folder 6: 10)
      - Millenson, Roy H., 1963 (Box-folder 6: 11)
      - Morgan, Thomas E., 1962 (Box-folder 6: 12)
      - Nixon, Richard, 1960 (Box-folder 6: 13)
      - O'Brien, Ruth M., 1963 (Box-folder 6: 14)
      - Phila, 1960 (Box-folder 6: 15)
      - Philbrick, Herbert A., 1966 (Box-folder 6: 16)
      - Power, Daniel E., 1967 (Box-folder 6: 17)
      - Prochazka, Adolph, 1967 (Box-folder 6: 18)
      - Putterman, Felix M., 1963 (Box-folder 6: 19)
      - Reed, Paul K., 1963 (Box-folder 6: 20)
      - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 1962 (Box-folder 6: 21)
      - Stearman, Lewis A., 1960 (Box-folder 6: 22)
      - Thornett, G. M., 1960-1963 (Box-folder 6: 23)
      - Walker, Weldon, 1966 (Box-folder 6: 24)
      - Webb, Maurice T., 1963 (Box-folder 6: 25)
  - Credo for independence of the Captive Nations, undated (Box-folder 6: 26)
  - Flyers, 1960, 1977 (Box-folder 6: 27)
  - General letters, 1961-1977 (Box-folder 6: 28-29)
    Letters addressed to the Committee from various state supporters and government officials regarding Captive Nations Week and other Committee logistics.
  - Honor roll, participation recognition, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 6: 30)
  - Letters to the President, 1962-1979 (Box-folder 6: 31)
  - Memoranda, 1960-1975 (Box-folder 6: 32)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1960-1981
    Articles cover President Carter’s signing of the Captive Nations Week Proclamation as well as Captive Nations Week Committee’s efforts to maintain participation in the annual Captive Nations Week Celebration. Includes clippings from the Alabama Post-Herald, Boston Christian Science Monitor, Buffalo Courier Express, Chicago Sun Times, Cincinnati Enquirer, Cleveland Plain Dealer, Dallas Times Herald, Flint Michigan Journal, Indianapolis Star, Indiana Herald, Knoxville Sentinel, Los Angeles Times, Louisville Times, Manchester Union-Leader, Michigan Free Press, Missouri Democrat Globe, Newark Star-Ledger, New York News, Oregon Dealer, Parkersburg Sentinel, Pennsylvania Herald, Riverside Press, Santa Monica Evening Outlook, Shenandoah Herald, Washington Capitol Spotlight, Washington Post, and West Virginia News.
    - 1960-1967 (Box-folder 6: 33)
    - 1976-1977 (Box-folder 6: 34)
    - 1978-1981 (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - Official government statements, 1960-1977 (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - Pamphlets, 1960-1967 (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - Prospectus, 1964 (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - Proclamations, 1960-1982
    Includes signed proclamations from various state mayors and presidents declaring a celebrated week for captive nations. Represents the National Captive Nation Committee’s efforts to maintain the Captive Nations List and ensure that every state recognized the annual Captive Nations Week.
    - 1960-1969 (Box-folder 7: 7)
    - 1975-1979 (Box-folder 7: 8)
    - 1980-1982 (Box-folder 7: 9)
  - Press releases, 1960-1982
    Includes statements condemning President Ford’s comment that there was no Soviet domination in Eastern Europe and President Carter’s late approval for the Captive Nations Proclamation. Also covered are the Committee’s promotion of human rights, events for the celebration of Captive Nations Week, joint congressional resolutions, planned demonstrations, promotions and appointments within the Committee, meetings and conferences, and updates from the Committee on the political changes taking place in non-democratic countries.
    - 1960-1969 (Box-folder 7: 5)
    - 1976-1982 (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - Radio script, 1967 (Box-folder 7: 10)
  - Resolutions, 1959-1982
    Includes formal resolutions voted and passed through Congress, which authorized and established Public Law No. 86-90, proclaiming the official national observance for Captive Nations Week from 1959 until 1982. Resolutions also include descriptions released by Congress explaining the need to recognize the injustices experienced throughout non-democratic countries and efforts made by the National Captive Nations Committee to promote awareness for captive nations.
    - 1959-1962 (Box-folder 7: 11)
    - 1976-1982 (Box-folder 7: 12)
  - Select source material on Captive Nations Week, Congressional Record, 1960-1964 (Box-folder 7: 13)
  - Sticker, Captive Nations, undated (Box-folder 7: 14)
- Ukrainian Congress Committee File, 1959-1983 (Boxes 7-8)
  Includes office files related to the Committee, including memoranda to government officials, newsletters, and press releases. Also included are incoming and outgoing letters from Edward J. Derwinski, Orest Shchudluk, and Yaroslav Stetsko, co-chairmen for the Committee, capturing their efforts to promote support throughout Congress for people living in non-democratic Ukraine. Subject matter includes appeals submitted by the Committee to state-signatories attending the Helsinki Review Conference to publically recognize violations made by the Soviet Union in regards to its anti-Ukrainian policies. Memoranda to cultural leaders, scholars, and statesmen ask for support for the Committee’s efforts towards achieving independence for Ukraine from communist control.
  - Appeals, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 7: 15)
  - Correspondence, 1963-1982
    - Edward J. Derwinski, 1963-1982
      - Hatfield, Mark O., 1963 (Box-folder 7: 16)
      - Hawkins, Augustus F., 1980 (Box-folder 7: 17)
      - Ku, Cheng-kang, 1982 (Box-folder 7: 18)
      - Nowak, Joseph W., 1963 (Box-folder 7: 19)
      - Rhodes, James A., 1965 (Box-folder 7: 20)
      - Tobriner, Walter N., 1965 (Box-folder 7: 21)
    - Orest Szczudluk, 1965
      - Conte, Silvio, 1965 (Box-folder 7: 22)
      - O'Neill, Thomas P., 1965 (Box-folder 7: 23)
      - Philbrin, Philip J., 1965 (Box-folder 7: 24)
    - Yaroslav Stetsko, 1977, 1982
      - Free Trade Union News, editor, 1977 (Box-folder 7: 25)
      - Woo, Jae-Seung, 1982 (Box-folder 7: 26)
  - Memoranda, 1965-1983
    - 1965-1979 (Box-folder 8: 1)
    - 1980-1983 (Box-folder 8: 2)
  - Press releases, 1975-1980 (Box-folder 8: 3)
  - The Ukrainian Bulletin, 1959-1966 (Box-folder 8: 4)
- United States and China after Mao Conference Committee File, 1976-1977 (Box 8)
  Includes press releases, programs, and memoranda from the United States and China after Mao Conference Committee relating to foreign policy issues of the 1970s, general myths behind the "One-China" concept, and recognizing the ongoing struggle between Nationalist China and Communist China. Dobriansky strongly supported the conference and attended to help the Carter administration formulate a foreign policy towards China.
  - Memorandum, 1976 November 6 (Box-folder 8: 5)
  - Press release, 1976 December 16 (Box-folder 8: 6)
  - Programs, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 8: 7)
- Printed Matter, 1959-1983 (Boxes 8-10)
  Conference programs, House and Senate addresses, memoranda, newsletters, newspapers, newspaper clippings, pamphlets, prayer scriptures, invitations, press releases, speeches, and booklets from various anti-communist organizations. Reflects Dobriansky's continuous efforts to support other non-democratic advocacy organizations around the world. Also includes Congressional Records from his extensive career as a consultant and his campaign for captive nations.
  - Booklets, 1960-1961
    - Decisions For A Better America, 1960 (Box-folder 8: 8)
    - Flags of the Captive Nations, Robert E. Ramsey, A.M. Printing Co., 1961 (Box-folder 8: 9)
  - Conference programs, 1976-1977, 1981
    - "The U.S. and USSR after Detente," Washington D.C., 1977 (Box-folder 8: 10)
    - "10th WACL and 23rd APACL," Taipei, 1977 (Box-folder 8: 11)
    - "The Ukrainian Catholic Metropolia," Drexel University, 1976 (Box-folder 8: 12)
    - "14th WACL and 27th APACL," Taipei, 1981 (Box-folder 8: 13)
  - Congressional Record, 1959-1983
    - 1959-1962 (Box-folder 8: 14)
    - 1963-1965 (Box-folder 8: 15)
    - 1965 (Box-folder 8: 16)
    - 1966 (Box-folder 8: 17)
    - 1967-1968 (Box-folder 9: 1)
    - 1968-1969 (Box-folder 9: 2)
    - 1970-1971 (Box-folder 9: 3)
    - 1971-1975 (Box-folder 9: 4)
    - 1976-1977 (Box-folder 9: 5)
    - 1977-1979 (Box-folder 9: 6)
    - 1980-1981 (Box-folder 9: 7)
    - 1982 (Box-folder 10: 1)
    - 1983 (Box-folder 10: 2)
  - Eulogy card, George Meany, 1980 (Box-folder 10: 3)
  - House and Senate addresses, 1980 (Box-folder 10: 4)
  - Joint communique, WACL, APACL and AYACL Conference, 1981 (Box-folder 10: 5)
  - Memoranda, World Anti-Communist League, 1976 (Box-folder 10: 6)
  - Newsletters, 1959-1982
    Contains newsletters from anti-communist advocacy organizations that Dobriansky supported and followed related to updates on the political situation in China and captive nations advocacy, and other general news.
    - AFL-CIO Free Trade Unions News, 1976 July (Box-folder 10: 7)
    - American Conservative Union Report, 1966 (Box-folder 10: 8)
    - The American Legion Monthly, 1964 (Box-folder 10: 9)
    - Americans to Free Captive Nations, Inc., 1977 July (Box-folder 10: 10)
    - Asian Outlook, 1965-1982 (Box-folder 10: 11)
    - Bulletin of the Antibolshivick Block of Nations, 1982 (Box-folder 10: 12)
    - Dollar Hollar News, 1966 (Box-folder 10: 13)
    - Free China Weekly, 1978 (Box-folder 10: 14)
    - Free China and Asia Monthly Report, 1959 (Box-folder 10: 15)
    - Freedom Facts Publication, 1962 (Box-folder 10: 16)
    - The New Guard, 1965 (Box-folder 10: 17)
    - News from China, 1967 (Box-folder 10: 18)
    - Pacific Cultural Foundation, 1982 (Box-folder 10: 19)
    - Scnia, Monthly News to Students on Captive Nations, undated (Box-folder 10: 20)
    - The Truth about China, 1978 (Box-folder 10: 21)
    - This Week in the Nation's Capital, 1960 (Box-folder 10: 22)
  - Newspapers, 1977-1982
    Includes The Truth, Ukrainian Fraternal Voice, Ukrainian Catholic Daily, and Free China Weekly, covering political news from various non-democratic nations.
    - 1977-1980 (Box-folder 10: 23)
    - 1981-1982 (Box-folder 10: 24)
  - Pamphlets, 1960-1981
    - Birthday Celebration for Walter Judd, 1977 (Box-folder 10: 25)
    - Prayer Scripture by Dr. Frederick Brown Harris, 1960 (Box-folder 10: 26)
    - Twenty-Seventh Sunday after Pentecost, St. John's Church service, 1978 (Box-folder 10: 27)
    - Victory Over Communism Rally, 1981 (Box-folder 10: 28)
  - Press releases, 1965-1979
    - National Press Building, 1977 (Box-folder 10: 29)
    - National Republican Heritage Groups Council, 1977 (Box-folder 10: 30)
    - The Right Side, 1977 (Box-folder 10: 31)
    - Senate joint statement, SALT II opposition, 1979 (Box-folder 10: 32)
    - USSR National Affairs Report, 1965 (Box-folder 10: 33)
  - Speeches, 1977, 1981
    Composed of two typed handouts of speeches given at events that Dobriansky attended, regarding President Carter recognizing the captive nations and anti-communist advocacy.
    - "A Carter Retreat on Human Rights," Lee Edwards, White House meeting, 1977 (Box-folder 10: 34)
    - "Stride Ahead Into the Era of Victory for Freedom," Ku Cheng-Kang, World Freedom Day Rally, 1981 (Box-folder 10: 35)
    - "Victory Over Communism," Ku Cheng-Kang, World Anti-Communist Rally, Taipei, 1981 (Box-folder 10: 36)
  - Text, USSR international affairs with the United States, 1977 (Box-folder 10: 37)
  - Conference program, "Human Rights after Helsinki," Washington D.C., 1977 (Box-folder 10: 38)
- Photographs, 1976, undated (Box 10)
  Includes two photographs related to Captive Nations Week observance and a photograph of Dobriansky alongside his close friends and Committee partners, Daniel J. Flood and Edward Derwinski.
  - Captive Nations Week, Fountain Square, Cincinnati, 1976 (Box-folder 10: 39)
  - Lev E. Dobriansky, Daniel J. Flood, and Edward J. Derwinski, undated (Box-folder 10: 40)
- Oversize Material, 1976-1981 (Box 11)
  Contains signed proclamations by the mayor of Los Angeles and various presidents, including Gerald R. Ford, Jimmy Carter, and Ronald Reagan. Also included is a large booklet published by the World Anti-Communist League, which contains charts of communists in China.
  - Charts Concerning Chinese Communists on the Mainland, World Anti-Communist League, China chapter, 1978 April (Box-folder 11: 1)
  - Proclamations, 1976-1981 (Box-folder 11: 2)